<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>alyx.io</title>
	<link href="http://alyx.io/" rel="self"/>
	<link href="http://alyx.io"/>
	<id>http://alyx.io</id>

	<author>
		<name>Alyx Mayer</name>
		<email>contact「@」alyx.io</email>
	</author>

	
	<entry>
		<title>Is Gender Inherently Oppressive?</title>
		<link href="http://alyx.io/feminism/2015/06/14/is-gender-inherently-oppressive/"/>
		<updated>2015/06/14</updated>
		<id>http://alyx.io/feminism/2015/06/14/is-gender-inherently-oppressive</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is common these days, while perhaps at least affirming that “sex” is socially constructed like “gender”, to consider the latter not inherently oppressive because many persyns identify with the concept. There must be something worth saving, the reasoning goes, for it to be considered an important part of many lives.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:butler&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:butler&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The justification is typically one of being inclusive to trans persyns, in contrast to the old and anti-trans feminism which would see gender disappear. I contend that this historical development in feminism betrays a profound ciscentricism. The changing theoretical approach to gender in mainstream feminism with the desire to include trans persyns perfectly mirrors the ciscentric idea that “only trans persyns identify with gender; cis persyns simply &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt;”. When confronted with trans persyns, the historical oddity of a feminism that suddenly finds a new approach to gender, thinking “look at all these persyns identifying with gender”, must answer the charge that identification with gender (whether by a trans or cis persyn) has been going on for centuries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As suspect as the history of this proposition is, we must also confront it head-on. If one believes that gender must be saved from the influences of patriarchy and the struggles of feminism alike, and not abolished in the very same moment and through the very same transformation of society that abolishes patriarchy, then one must also consider gender to be permanent and inevitable, a ‘natural law of humynity’, for the fact that there is no sensible explanation for why gender was initially produced, and why it is now continually reproduced, without making reference to class society: something we must abolish, and something which would thus implicate gender as inherently oppressive. The only thing left is to nullify the question in the first place by saying that gender is an ever-present aspect of the humyn condition: that the reactionaries are right and gender is “humyn nature”. This works because a gender that has always existed has made witness to all make and manner of society – from a world of primitive communist classlessness to a world beset by parasitic nations feeding on imperial blood – and so class and gender must possess some level of independence as &lt;em&gt;fundamentally&lt;/em&gt; historically discrete phenomena. If some claim to “materialism” is to be made, and if the proposition that oppressive productive relations spawned gender as a related oppressive social relation has been logically ruled out for contradicting the initial premise, then what &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be pointed to as the cause of gender? Or even just the cause of patriarchy? Again, we have to turn to saying that gender is inevitable. Thus the question of whether gender is inherently oppressive and whether it has always existed are one and the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with saying that gender has always existed is that ideas do not fall from the sky. We have elaborate ideas about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; certain persyns should be assigned to particular groups, elaborate ideas about &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; each of us are in light of our assigned group, elaborate ideas about &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; these groups are, and elaborate ideas about &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; society as a whole should be structured in support of the existence of said social stratification. Such ideas about society and their structural expression and reproduction through the arrangement of society don’t just “happen” through coincidence, chance, will, or innateness – except in the eyes of the bankrupt idealist. Social existence breeds social consciousness, which breeds social action, which in turn shapes social existence. The only way to break with the view of gender as a characteristic of a historically specific type of society is to break with the dialectical materialist notion of the cycle of &lt;code&gt;material world → ideas → material world&lt;/code&gt; and say that ideas – gender in this case – are something existing not as a product of the interaction between our brains, our perceived world, and our actions upon the world, but as something privileged over material reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that wasn’t enough, we can also consider the impossibility of explaining or understanding the genderedness or non-genderedness of something without making reference to gender roles – something any self-respecting feminist aims to abolish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one can provide the correct answer as to why and how the concept of “red” or “purple” acquires social meaning, then one can also begin to provide the correct answer as to why and how “womyn” or “man” aquires social meaning. Once the basics of the process for the establishment of any particular social meaning is understood (apparently an incredibly challenging concept to many!) then the only question remaining is: in creating the social meaning of “womyn” or “man”, how different are these practices to the practices of gender roles? Are they not the same? When the social meaning of “womyn” is created by someone saying or reinforcing the idea that “wimmin are the ones who like pink”, then only an anti-feminist would say that is not a gender role, only the most befuddled failure of a feminist would say that this is not actually the construction of the social meaning of “womyn”, and even the most imaginative of a feminist could not hope to invent a sensible proposition for the construction of the social meaning of “womyn” outside of the practice of gender roles such as this. To reiterate, if we’re to keep with dialectical materialism then there’s no such thing as a metaphysical “womyn” out there that exists apart from the results of humyn activity. Gender, as a social construct, must be determined by social activity to possess any meaning – to even exist at all – and this activity we call the imposition and practice of gender roles. When a frilly dress is “womyn”, that’s a gender role; when a particular body part is “womyn”, that’s a gender role. And it also holds true in the reverse perspective: when “womyn” is a frilly dress, that’s a gender role; when “womyn” is a particular body part, that’s a gender role. From whichever way one looks at things, and squirm and wriggle as one might, it’s gender roles all the way down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one is to turn to “biology” in hope of finding cause or reason for the natural or inevitable existence of gender, prepare for disappointment. There is no neurological difference between the “genders” outside of “the ‘drip, drip, drip’ of gender stereotyping”.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:drip&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:drip&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; What little difference that does exist, being commonly exaggerated through bad science and patriarchal fantasy, is easily explained through the combination of neuroplasticity and patriarchal society. What this means is that gender cannot be an inevitable result of a humyn need to express one’s inner, biological, pre-social, pre-oppression, inclinations to gender. It’s not the gendered brain creating a gendered society as a reflection of itself – it’s precisely the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to sum things up: the initial cause of gender can’t be found in heaven upon high, for that’s simply objective idealism. Nor can gender be found innately within us, for that’s simply primitive subjective idealism as no one could possibly have an ex-cultural or pre-cultural conception of a social system. Nor can the cause of gender be found “biologically”, for there’s simply no neurological basis for it (as even bourgeois science is finally and reluctantly concluding).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gender &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt;, however, be found in the relations of production.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:engels&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:engels&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It’s an imminent reality today due to class society; it’s fundamentally and irrevocably a hierarchy of oppression, exploitation, and domination. The genesis of gender is in the genesis of oppression and exploitation, and the exodus of gender is in the exodus of oppression and exploitation. Gender is thus an artifact of a particular stage of society, and has not always existed, just as assuredly as oppression and exploitation has not always existed. Through revolution and the fight against class society and patriarchy, gender will wither away as part of the transition to communism. While we can look at hormones or dresses in our current patriarchal society and be haunted by pernicious thoughts of “gender”, in a non-patriarchal society these things will cease to possess any structural meaning and become as socially irrelevant as attached or detached earlobes are to our current society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the most basic political level, to forget or deny all of this is to rip the emancipatory potential from feminism. If we’re not to destroy the social group “man/male”, and gender as a whole, then patriarchy has won and we cannot do anything but resign ourselves to a “neocolonial” type of “equality” between constructs inseparable from the very thing we say we’re struggling against: oppression and exploitation. That’s not a kind of world worth fighting for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what is your line? Let us consider the varying definitions of “man”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, there’s the blatantly patriarchal position – “men are strong bearded lumberjacks; men have a penis because ‘man’ and ‘male’ are the same thing; gender is not inherently oppressive”. This deserves no consideration, and can be axiomatically discarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, there’s the “cis radical feminist” position – “men are the sex-class male, and this group exerts structural domination over the sex-class female by creating the gender groups ‘wimmin’ and ‘men’; men have a penis because only males are made men by society; gender is inherently oppressive”. This can be discarded for the naturalisation of the category of “sex”, and the failure to explain the trans experience.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:tpdsg&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:tpdsg&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; As MacKinnon said, “Male dominant society has defined women as a discrete biological group forever. If this was going to produce liberation, we’d be free”.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:mackinnon&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:mackinnon&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, there’s the “liberal feminist” position – “men are those who express a ‘man’ identity; men have some divergence in anatomy, and do not have a penis by definition; gender is not inherently oppressive”. This can be discarded for the naturalisation of the category of “identity”,&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:eg&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:eg&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and the positioning of gender as an ever-present aspect of “humyn nature”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, there’s the dialectical materialist position – “men are the group of persyns positioned as ‘men’ by society, and this group exerts structural domination over those positioned as as ‘non-men’ by society; men have some divergence in anatomy, and do not have a penis by definition; gender is inherently oppressive”. According to this, trans wimmin are wimmin because they are so socially placed by patriarchy as to be subject to a subordinate relation to sexuality;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:sexuality&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:sexuality&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; because they are placed just as cis wimmin are through rape and sexual assault and objectification and abuse and pornification and prostitution. If gender ultimately does not exist outside of oppression, then to feminism “womyn” just a matter of politics: who’s subordinated to patriarchy in actual practice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s not sacrifice feminism on the altar of biology or identity any more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:butler&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“[G]ender can be very important to us, and some people really love the gender that they have claimed for themselves. If gender is eradicated, so too is an important domain of pleasure for many people. And others have a strong sense of self bound up with their genders, so to get rid of gender would be to shatter their self-hood.” – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.transadvocate.com/gender-performance-the-transadvocate-interviews-judith-butler_n_13652.htm&quot;&gt;Gender Performance: The TransAdvocate interviews Judith Butler&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:butler&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:drip&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/science/science-news/10684179/Men-and-women-do-not-have-different-brains-claims-neuroscientist.html&quot;&gt;Men and women do not have different brains, claims neuroscientist&lt;/a&gt;; See also: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2015/10/151029185544.htm&quot;&gt;Meta-analysis of 76 published papers shows no difference in hippocampal size between men and women&lt;/a&gt; and “Delusions of Gender” by Cordelia Fine. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:drip&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:engels&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marxists.org/archive/marx/works/1884/origin-family/&quot;&gt;The Origin of the Family, Private Property and the State&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:engels&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:tpdsg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Another article of mine talks about this more: &lt;a href=&quot;https://alyx.io/feminism/2014/05/24/trans-people-and-dialectics-of-sex-and-gender/&quot;&gt;Trans People and the Dialectics of Sex and Gender&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:tpdsg&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:mackinnon&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.transadvocate.com/sex-gender-and-sexuality-the-transadvocate-interviews-catharine-a-mackinnon_n_15037.htm&quot;&gt;Sex, Gender, and Sexuality: The TransAdvocate interviews Catharine A. MacKinnon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:mackinnon&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:eg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Another article of mine talks about this more: &lt;a href=&quot;https://alyx.io/feminism/2014/12/17/the-eroticisation-of-gender/&quot;&gt;The Eroticisation of Gender&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:eg&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:sexuality&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;https://alyx.io/feminism/2014/12/17/the-eroticisation-of-gender/&quot;&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt;, although mentioned throughout, I failed to really elaborate on what the “gender hierarchy” concretely means. The usual marxist summation of gender/patriarchy would be something like: “a system for the subordination of wimmin to a reproductive/household division of labour”. I draw on &lt;a href=&quot;/library/mackinnon/&quot;&gt;Catherine MacKinnon&lt;/a&gt; in my rejection of this. A full reinterpretation or reconcilation of MacKinnon’s main conclusion with marxism is outside of the scope of this article, but will be forthcoming. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:sexuality&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Eroticisation of Gender</title>
		<link href="http://alyx.io/feminism/2014/12/17/the-eroticisation-of-gender/"/>
		<updated>2014/12/17</updated>
		<id>http://alyx.io/feminism/2014/12/17/the-eroticisation-of-gender</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is a follow-up of sorts to &lt;a href=&quot;https://alyx.io/feminism/2014/05/24/trans-people-and-dialectics-of-sex-and-gender/&quot;&gt;Trans People and the Dialectics of Sex and Gender: Against Radical and Liberal Feminism&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cause of so much confusion over the nature of gender is that gender is a construct of unparalleled proximity. Gender is a construct of the &lt;em&gt;private home&lt;/em&gt;, of the confines of the bedroom and the kitchen. It’s the construct of &lt;em&gt;intimacy&lt;/em&gt;. It’s the construct that must invest in drawing up personal barriers due to the relative impossibility of more traditional barriers. It’s the construct that, by necessity – due to the closeness between “husband and wife” within the private household – creates the most deeply held personal ideology. I’m not talking about a difference in severity here, just a difference in the way it is reproduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Class and national oppression are reproduced at a relative distance. The bourgeoisie, the whites, they don’t have as much contact – certainly not as much contact of the intimate kind – with the groups lower on the hierarchy. It is easy to enforce “racial” distinctions without resorting to individual ideology and personal identity as much, because these distinctions are generally enforced across borders – across entire communities, regions, or nations. There is a comparatively clear-cut separation. Entire families are usually racialized the same way, and in the private sphere there isn’t much “mixing” between “races”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we imagine a society where the bourgeoisie mixes socially, sexually, personally, and in every other kind of intimate manner, with the proletariat in perfect proportion to the percentage of the population they make up, then this society would be a very different society from our current reality. In our society, the bourgeois live in gated communities, in rich suburbs, or affluent postcodes. They inter-marry with other bourgeois, and create new bourgeois when they reproduce. Social mobility is a myth, class is semi-hereditary, and capitalism is only slightly better than feudalism in this regard. Members of the bourgeoisie don’t have any intimate interaction with the members of the proletariat; if they are to get close and interact with the proletariat, then it isn’t the intimate kind of closeness like the closeness of the family. It’s the sort of closeness of a barked order, of a wage packet, of hiring or firing, of the ownership of the means of production that the proletariat operates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gender is another matter entirely. If we imagine a society where men mixed (in both intimate and non-intimate contexts) with women in perfect proportion to the percentage of the population that women make up, and &lt;em&gt;vise-versa&lt;/em&gt;, then this society would not be too different from the one we live in. It is considered the ultimate destiny – the sole and divinely ordained purpose – of woman and man to join together, to become one, and create their own private sphere together. Gender isn’t hereditary like class and nation is since the husband and wife are tasked with the extension of themselves and their sphere through the production of new husbands and wives. Effectively, the family functions as a self-replicating unit, constructed from two people of radically different positions in the gender hierarchy, and tasked with the creation new people of differing positions in the very same hierarchy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if the division between husbands and wives (and the future husbands and wives they produce) in the family – and ultimately the division between woman and man – can’t be so overtly enforced at a relative distance like class and nation divisions are, then how is gender oppression propagated? What options gain increased importance due to the relative impossibility of others?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intimacy requires, and enables, that the ratio of the “subjective-coercive” mechanism (coercion in the form of ideology) to the “objective-coercive” mechanism (coercion in the form of force, or the threat thereof; the standard definition of “coercion”) be much greater in gender than it is class or nation. Gender role education makes up one aspect of this “subjective-coercive” mechanism. But for the family unit to function as it currently does, it isn’t enough for the “different genders” to each receive their own specialized education. It needs to go further than that. These gender roles, once learned, must then be put into practice, and for this to happen as it currently does, we have the other aspect to the “subjective-coercive” mechanism: gender identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both aspects heavily rely on each other to function and give each other meaning. Patriarchy needs us to believe that gender and gender roles are inherent to us so that we behave appropriately – not out of service to others, or because we were overtly coerced – but in service to ourselves and our natural inclinations and needs. We must be educated to want out of our own hearts, and to deeply &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt;, our gender (roles). Our genders and our selves are produced by society; patriarchy is the subject, gender is the verb, we’re the object, and gender identity is the result. For the oppressed to self-police, and really internalize their subjugated role, is a huge win for patriarchy. Likewise, for the oppressors to police themselves and the subjugated, and really internalize their subjugator role, is a huge win for patriarchy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If gender identity somehow didn’t exist as an aspect of patriarchy, then patriarchy wouldn’t be as strong. Removing gender identity, we have two options to keep the same level of patriarchy as before: decrease the level of intimacy, or increase the level of the “objective-coercive” mechanism. The relative amount of intimacy is fundamental to the arrangement of patriarchy, so the only thing left to do is to increase the relative amount of the “objective-coercive” mechanism, but an increase in this &lt;em&gt;couldn’t&lt;/em&gt; happen with gender identity gone because it’s men who need to enforce the violence (on a relatively intimate level, don’t forget!), and it’s gender identity that helps this happen in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, just before we continue, let me make it absolutely clear that &lt;em&gt;cis people gender identify just as much as trans people do&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; real difference between the two is that when cis people gender identify, it’s approved by cissexist society. Patriarchy is incredibly invested in making sure that people develop gender identity on it’s own terms, but trans people are a threat to this. We must treat this fact very carefully. We need to figure out how to approach gender identity ultimately being a product of patriarchy without further marginalising trans people. Generally, I think it would be ultra-left (with rightist consequences, like all ultra-leftism) to start pointing this out in everyday political contexts, given that cis people don’t view themselves as having gender identities, and so in their eyes this would be nothing but an attack on trans people. Just like we as communists support bourgeois-democratic revolutions in oppressed nations against imperialism (whilst still acknowledging the need for proletarian revolution), we also support trans people against cissexism and their right to gender identity on the same terms as cis people (whilst still acknowledging that gender/identity would not exist without patriarchy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For brievity, I’ll call the turning of gender into an identity, whether on a personal or a theoretical level, “the eroticisation of gender”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liberal feminists exemplify the eroticisation of gender when they say that women are oppressed because they identify as women. As well as confusing up from down, symptom with cause, and basically mistaking the floor for the ceiling, this is an obvious idealist mistake because of the simple matter that if we waved a magic wand and made every woman in the world stop identifying as women, then patriarchy would not completely disappear!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An identity-based definition of gender falls down in other places, too. Since coming out to others as a trans, I first identified as a woman, then as non-binary, then as a woman again, and then I finally rejected identity. Despite all the changes in my identity, the only thing that actually changed my position in patriarchy was coming out as trans. Identity is a useless way to analyze my experience. Likewise, I used to know a really femme cis gay man. Saying that “he identified as a man” is just a banality. What matters is structural relationships. He wasn’t treated, in a gendered way, like the average man. He was treated as a very atypical man by patriarchy, and that’s what really matters. Since gender/identity is a product of patriarchy, and there’s no redeeming it, there’s no reason to be prescriptive in our statements here, within the context of our revolutionary theory, and say that “since men should be allowed to be femme and gay, we should say that femme gay men are men, full stop”. Only the descriptive route is actually useful when we’re trying to understand society. Prescriptivism should be saved for activist contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about radical feminists, when they turn gender into biology? They make some slipshod attempt at materialism and rising above the erotic by saying all women are women because they were “born female” and all men are men because they were “born male”, because that’s what “woman” and “man” is constructed from by patriarchy. As I pointed out earlier, though, they’re just as wrong as the liberals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[A]n individual person’s “sex”, as decided by society, doesn’t completely determine their relationship to sexism. Designation at birth isn’t some metaphysical essence that’s imparted on someone for life, entirely and necessarily coloring all further social interactions. Designation at birth is of course an incredibly powerful predictor of the ensuing privileges, socialization, and sex education society places upon someone, and this absolutely cannot be denied. But as ever, as with all generalisations, it isn’t correct in every case.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Confusion of the conditions for the creation and development of oppressor and oppressed classes with the conditions for oppression in a mostly individual context is one of the most infuriating aspects of radical feminism. The categories of “&lt;abbr title=&quot;Designated Female At Birth&quot;&gt;DFAB&lt;/abbr&gt;” and “&lt;abbr title=&quot;Designated Male At Birth&quot;&gt;DMAB&lt;/abbr&gt;” developed in tandem with the development of the gender hierarchy, but that doesn’t mean that each individual person’s place in the gender hierarchy is necessarily what one would traditionally expect for a person of their birth designation. To think otherwise is a classic misunderstanding of the relationship between the aggregate and the particular.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:tpdsg&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:tpdsg&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To step around these problems in the two major ways of defining gender, I contend that it’s the gendering that one receives from society that makes the gender. As revolutionaries we need to understand that it harms our project to truly understand and change society if we treat “woman” and “man” as anything other than scientific terms to be used based on an objective assessment of someone’s position in patriarchy. It’s an extremely sad state of affairs that the veil of eroticism has kept us from understanding gender from a power point of view. When we say that someone is petty-bourgeois we don’t look to their identity, but to their relation to production. If we can already do it with other social positions like class, why can’t we do it with gender? Why can’t we look to relation to patriarchy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does “look to relation to patriarchy” mean concretely, though? If we accept the fact that sex is a social construct and something that is not necessarily determinant of someone’s gender, but is an institutional basis for gender, then we free ourselves up to simply looking at how someone is treated by patriarchy. What is their place in the hierarchy? Do they possess gendered power or are they a victim of gendered power? Do they face sexual violence or control? What gender roles are forced upon them? Are they the objectifier or the objectified? These are the sorts of questions we should ask, not the arrangement of genitals or identity, but the broad position within patriarchal society as assigned by patriarchal society itself. The relations of oppression are what matter because that’s fundamentally what patriarchy is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve said earlier:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When I say “I’m a woman” I’m not saying I innately “feel like a woman” (I don’t think you can ever construct a non-patriarchal justification for that), I’m instead relating myself to other women and our somewhat shared experience as a group under patriarchy. I’m stating that my material interests and experience of the world are aligned with womanhood; my liberation is therefore fundamentally and intimately bound up with other women, and thus as far as I’m concerned, “woman” describes me.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:tpdsg:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:tpdsg&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;・ ・ ・&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In western society, gender is &lt;em&gt;de jure&lt;/em&gt; binary. This statement will raise no objections from anyone. What about &lt;em&gt;de facto&lt;/em&gt;, though? If gender isn’t biology, &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; identity, then as I said, the only thing left that we can define gender with is “one’s relation to the gender hierarchy”. Based on this, taking a look at the positions within current patriarchal society, we come to the inescapable conclusion that western society is &lt;em&gt;de facto&lt;/em&gt; a trigender society. What we have are “men”, “women”, and “gender outlaws”.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:bornstein&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:bornstein&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail scale-image&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2014-12-17-the-eroticisation-of-gender/gender.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2014-12-17-the-eroticisation-of-gender/gender.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
	
	
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Image credit: based on a sketch by Zoë Meinhof)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one talks about the gender outlaws. You won’t find any official recognition of them, you won’t find a ‘☣’ symbol (or something) joining ‘F’ and ‘M’ in the list of valid birth certificate stamps. They’re the people that patriarchy has no use for, and doesn’t like to admit to: the outcasts, the “freaks”, the unintelligibles. Going back to the intimacy of gender, and the truly elaborate nature of gender roles, it’s inevitable for there to be those who fall between the cracks. If patriarchy does happen to recognize the gender outlaws, then it’s a recognition of the threat they pose to, or their incompatibility with, the current order. Gender outlaws are the people who must be shoved back into one of the &lt;em&gt;de jure&lt;/em&gt; positions: “housewife” or “lumberjack”, “male” or “female”. Failing this they must be exterminated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trans women are perhaps the biggest gender outlaws. No one wastes any second of any day telling us that we’re the sex “male” or the gender “man”, yet neither do they ignore any chance to treat us as anything &lt;em&gt;but&lt;/em&gt; males or men. Despite the assertion to the contrary on a &lt;em&gt;de jure&lt;/em&gt; level by society, trans women are &lt;em&gt;de facto&lt;/em&gt; “non men” because we exist as targets for extreme gender oppression. I think that the degree that each trans woman is “trans-gendered” by society is generally the degree that they are gendered “outlaws” by society. The trans women who face more transmisogyny (because they are perceived as more trans and less cis) are more “outlaws” and less “women” than the trans women who face a lower amount of transmisogyny. This also applies to the degree that one deviates from the cult of heterosexuality. Non-heterosexual men and women objectively exist closer to the “outlaw” end of the power structure than heterosexual men and women. Sexuality and gender are very closely related, and queer politics is the politics of the gender outlaws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about non-binary trans people, though? What’s their structural relation to patriarchy, where do they fit in this trigender model, and what’s the most accurate descriptive statement about them? I apply the same answer here as with everyone: “their gender is whatever their structural place in patriarchy is”. So if non-binary people are “non-binary”, it’s not because of their identity, but to the degree that they are placed outside of the binary by society (i.e., the degree to which they are gender outlaws). Of course asserting an identity like “agender” can make one a target for being outlawed, but this doesn’t make “agender” really exist from a non-erotic point of view because “agender” is not a discrete way of being gendered and placed into the gender hierarchy by patriarchy. While the vast majority of people saying that they are “women” or “men” engage in &lt;em&gt;every bit as much&lt;/em&gt; gender eroticism as non-binary people do, “woman” and “man” coincidentally happen to exist from a non-erotic point of view, and by and large the people who identify as one of the de jure genders also tend to actually be placed into that position within the gender hierarchy by society, just because patriarchy tries hard to cultivate an “appropriate” gender identity in everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that when we talk about “non-binary”, it would be eurocentric to attempt to apply that term to societies/contexts that have more than two (&lt;em&gt;de jure&lt;/em&gt;) genders. “Non-binary” is only applicable to a society/context where there is a &lt;em&gt;de jure&lt;/em&gt; binary to define itself against; it’s a relative term for a relative concept. If a given society had genders X, Y, and Z, then the equivalent term to “non-binary” in that society would be “non-trinary”. All three genders, X, Y, and Z would exist from a non-erotic point of view within that society, just because that’s how people in that society can get gendered, meaning that those genders are objective positions within the gender hierarchy of that society/context. Taking a tri-gender gender system and putting it into a diagram, just for an example, we might end up with something that looks vaguely like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail scale-image&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2014-12-17-the-eroticisation-of-gender/gender2.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2014-12-17-the-eroticisation-of-gender/gender2.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
	
	
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A rough measure of how patriarchal any given society is can be found in the relative size of the “gender outlaw” gender versus officially sanctioned (&lt;em&gt;de jure&lt;/em&gt;) genders (this won’t apply in all cases, but should be true in the aggregate). In some societies the &lt;em&gt;de jure&lt;/em&gt; genders take up much more space relative to the gender outlaw gender, meaning less people are forced to be outlaws, and more people can exist as one of the less oppressed &lt;em&gt;de jure&lt;/em&gt; genders. Other types of less patriarchal societies, instead of having each &lt;em&gt;de jure&lt;/em&gt; gender take up more space, will instead have more &lt;em&gt;de jure&lt;/em&gt; genders, with the same end result – that the society is more forgiving of gendered difference because the range of non-outlawed positions within the gender hierarchy is larger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;・ ・ ・&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, turning gender into a subjective matter, making it something based not on society but on oneself and one’s feelings, is nothing but misogyny. “Woman” and “man” are concrete positions within a social hierarchy, but when we eroticise gender we confuse this. We end up obscuring the functioning of patriarchy, naturalizing gender, and falling to bourgeois individualism. Eroticising gender inevitably leads to reformism because if gender is an identity, not a relation to patriarchy, then “gender is an inevitable occurrence because it must have existed before patriarchy”, and so the best we can do is “reform gender, because gender will never disappear”. To justify gender reformism, perhaps the most highly developed gender eroticist, Judith Butler, says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[G]ender can be very important to us, and some people really love the gender that they have claimed for themselves. If gender is eradicated, so too is an important domain of pleasure for many people. And others have a strong sense of self bound up with their genders, so to get rid of gender would be to shatter their self-hood.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:jb-interview&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:jb-interview&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using pleasure as a metric for legitimacy under patriarchy is ceeding ground to patriarchy because patriarchy constructs pleasure in its own image. In the manufacturing of consent to patriarchy of the participants, patriarchy requires that women enjoy their own domination. Although most feminists don’t like to admit this, significant numbers – somewhere in the 31% and 57% range – of women have rape fantasies.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:rape-fantasies&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:rape-fantasies&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; They get themselves off on the idea of male ownership of their bodies. They treat what is perhaps the purest expression of patriarchy as something pleasurable, as erotic, as a nice fuck. Why, then, should we be surprised when people treat gender itself as something similar to a “nice fuck”? When the person-object who’s gendered and acted upon by the patriarchy-subject starts enjoying their own objectification (in both senses of the word), then that’s to be expected because it’s just how intimacy functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As MIM quite rightly pointed out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s not possible to say that women and men have had unequal power for centuries and then pretend that much of women’s behavior relative to men is not some kind of adjustment to that inequality.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:mim-theory&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:mim-theory&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, and to switch up Beauvoir’s famous words: &lt;strong&gt;One is not born female or woman, nor does one identify as such, but rather, one becomes female and woman&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:tpdsg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://alyx.io/feminism/2014/05/24/trans-people-and-dialectics-of-sex-and-gender/&quot;&gt;Trans People and the Dialectics of Sex and Gender: Against Radical and Liberal Feminism&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:tpdsg&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:tpdsg:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:bornstein&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;After writing this, it has been repeatedly brought up that a writer called Kate Bornstein once used the term “gender outlaw” [in a different way!] 30 years ago in some obscure book. I was not aware of this, and am not referencing Bornstein’s work in any way, shape or form. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:bornstein&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:jb-interview&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.transadvocate.com/gender-performance-the-transadvocate-interviews-judith-butler_n_13652.htm&quot;&gt;Gender Performance: The TransAdvocate interviews Judith Butler&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:jb-interview&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:rape-fantasies&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;According to a meta-review of 20 studies. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/00224490701808191&quot;&gt;Women’s Erotic Rape Fantasies: An Evaluation of Theory and Research&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:rape-fantasies&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:mim-theory&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prisoncensorship.info/archive/books/mt/mt2_3.pdf&quot;&gt;MIM Theory 2/3 – Gender and Revolutionary Feminism&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:mim-theory&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>How Much of the Labour in the World is Performed by Women?</title>
		<link href="http://alyx.io/capitalism/2014/09/29/how-much-of-world-labour-is-performed-by-women/"/>
		<updated>2014/09/29</updated>
		<id>http://alyx.io/capitalism/2014/09/29/how-much-of-world-labour-is-performed-by-women</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most feminists have heard the soundbite “women are 50% of the population, do &lt;em&gt;66% of the work&lt;/em&gt;, receive 10% of the income and own less than 1% of property” before, but it’s rarely backed up by a citation. If a citation &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; provided, it just points to a repetition of the same assertion made at an earlier date, rather than actual research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This “66%” number is even more suspect because it is always included alongside the false “less than 1% of property” statistic, and it’s an awfully round and convenient number, like all of the other numbers in the terrible little meme. 93.68% of statistics are made up on the spot, and this looks like one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I’ll attempt to calculate the labour hours per week (paid and unpaid; domestic and non-domestic; child care and adult care) performed by women and men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bias&quot;&gt;Bias&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please bear in mind that the conclusions here will probably understate the true burden of labour on women:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This data is based on self-reporting, and as such will likely underestimate the labour hours put in by women, and overrestimate the labour hours put in by men.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The most marginalised women, undocumented immigrants, trafficked women, women working in underground economies, and so on, are systematically excluded from these types of surveys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result for the semi-periphery and third world isn’t the most reliable of results, as the number of countries sampled is small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sources&quot;&gt;Sources&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is based on time-use surveys &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/gender/data/balancingpaidworkunpaidworkandleisure.htm&quot;&gt;from the OECD&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.actionaid.org/publications/making-care-visible&quot;&gt;from ActionAid&lt;/a&gt;. The spreadsheet I used is available &lt;a href=&quot;/uploads/2014-09-29-how-much-of-world-labour-is-performed-by-women/womens-share-of-labour.ods&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The “F:M” column gives the ratio of the total amount of female labour to the total amount of male labour, and vise versa for the “M:F” column.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The “{F/M} {paid/unpaid}” columns give the number of minutes of labour per day by gender and type of work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;first-world&quot;&gt;First world&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table-responsive&quot;&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;table table-striped&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Country&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;F:M&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;M:F&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;F Paid&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;F Unpaid&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;M Paid&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;M Unpaid&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Australia&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.039&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.963&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;128.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;303.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;248.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;167.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Austria&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.053&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.949&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;195.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;265.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;307.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;130.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Belgium&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.062&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.941&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;125.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;242.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;202.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;143.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.060&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.943&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;201.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;249.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;268.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;156.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Denmark&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.986&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.014&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;147.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;241.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;211.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;182.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Estonia&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.122&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.891&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;198.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;286.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;264.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;168.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Finland&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.099&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.910&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;159.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;229.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;199.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;154.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;France&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.177&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.850&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;116.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;262.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;173.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;149.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Germany&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.054&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.949&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;134.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;262.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;222.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;154.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Hungary&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.135&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.881&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;171.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;268.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;261.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;126.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ireland&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.078&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.927&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;142.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;289.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;280.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;120.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Italy&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.256&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.796&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;135.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;346.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;268.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;115.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Japan&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.134&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.882&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;178.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;320.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;375.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;64.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Korea&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.204&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.831&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;167.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;226.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;282.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;44.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Netherlands&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.020&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.981&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;146.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;274.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;279.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;133.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;New Zealand&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.007&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.993&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;160.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;259.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;279.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;137.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Norway&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.122&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.891&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;185.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;215.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;251.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;105.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Poland&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.104&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.906&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;136.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;294.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;234.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;156.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Portugal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.278&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.782&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;179.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;326.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;300.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;95.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Slovenia&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.135&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.881&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;169.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;286.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;236.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;165.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Spain&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.040&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.961&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;195.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;249.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;280.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;146.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Sweden&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.965&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.036&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;212.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;183.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;268.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;142.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UK&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.124&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.890&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;169.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;310.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;259.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;166.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;US&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.058&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.946&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;192.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;239.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;253.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;154.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Average&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.096&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.916&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;164.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;268.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;258.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;136.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;semi-periphery&quot;&gt;Semi-periphery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table-responsive&quot;&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;table table-striped&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Country&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;F:M&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;M:F&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;F Paid&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;F Unpaid&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;M Paid&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;M Unpaid&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mexico&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.112&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.899&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;161.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;372.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;368.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;111.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Turkey&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.114&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.898&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;73.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;353.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;282.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;101.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;China&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.158&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.863&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;228.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;233.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;308.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;90.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;South Africa&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.289&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.776&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;127.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;256.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;207.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;91.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Average&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.168&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.859&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;147.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;303.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;291.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;98.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;third-world&quot;&gt;Third world&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table-responsive&quot;&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;table table-striped&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Country&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;F:M&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;M:F&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;F Paid&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;F Unpaid&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;M Paid&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;M Unpaid&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;India&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.355&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.738&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;149.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;351.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;318.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;51.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Kenya&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.388&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.720&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;82.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;676.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;148.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;398.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Nepal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.445&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.692&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;73.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;628.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;160.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;325.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Nigeria&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.141&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.876&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;69.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;762.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;80.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;648.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Uganda&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.116&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.896&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;103.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;589.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;448.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;172.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Average&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.289&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0.784&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;95.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;601.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;230.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;318.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;analysis&quot;&gt;Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very briefly,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first world, Sweden and Denmark are obvious outliers. The data shows that, in those countries, women perform less labour than men. Unless patriarchy suddenly ended there and I just didn’t get the memo,  I can fairly confidently speculate that this points to &lt;strong&gt;a systematic underreporting of female vs male labour accross all countries&lt;/strong&gt;, like I predicted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the data still shows that the saying “women hold up half the sky” is incorrect. &lt;strong&gt;Women, in fact, hold up more than half the sky.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;scale-image&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014-09-29-how-much-of-world-labour-is-performed-by-women/share-of-labour.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of particular note is the triple burden. Not only do women work more hours, but they work more hours in unpaid jobs, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the hours they are paid for are paid at a lower wage than men. This, of course, has repercussions for women in the face of domestic violence (and misogyny as a whole) as, generally, there is a huge economic dependency on men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;scale-image&quot; src=&quot;/images/2014-09-29-how-much-of-world-labour-is-performed-by-women/share-of-unpaid.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that women perform the majority of the labour in the world, this points to the existence of a certain stratum of women and men – some of the ones who already economically benefit from the exploitation of the proletariat – who can also be said to economically benefit from patriarchy and the super-exploitation of women it results in, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Western DPRK Propaganda: The Worst, Occasionally Hilarious, and Often Racist, Lies</title>
		<link href="http://alyx.io/marxism/2014/08/14/western-dprk-propaganda/"/>
		<updated>2014/08/14</updated>
		<id>http://alyx.io/marxism/2014/08/14/western-dprk-propaganda</id>
		<content type="html">
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>“Quotations From Chairman Mao Zedong” Unix Fortune File</title>
		<link href="http://alyx.io/gnu/linux/2014/06/16/quotations-from-chairman-mao-unix-fortunes/"/>
		<updated>2014/06/16</updated>
		<id>http://alyx.io/gnu/linux/2014/06/16/quotations-from-chairman-mao-unix-fortunes</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-success text-center&quot;&gt;
	Download: &lt;a class=&quot;alert-link&quot; href=&quot;/uploads/2014-06-16-quotations-from-chairman-mao-unix-fortunes/Little-Red-Book&quot;&gt;Little-Red-Book&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the Marxist-Leninist-Maoist unix/fortune users (all 3 of you!), I present the entire &lt;em&gt;Quotations from Chairman Mao Zedong&lt;/em&gt; book in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortune_%28Unix%29&quot;&gt;fortune(6)&lt;/a&gt; ready format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the file above, then run the following command in the download directory to install:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;strfile Little-Red-Book Little-Red-Book.dat&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; sudo mv Little-Red-Book /usr/share/games/fortunes/&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; sudo mv Little-Red-Book.dat /usr/share/games/fortunes/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-muted&quot;&gt;Note: &lt;code&gt;/usr/share/games/fortunes/&lt;/code&gt; may not be the directory used by the version of fortune your distribution ships. Check the &quot;FILES&quot; section in your man page if this doesn&#39;t work.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Trans People and the Dialectics of Sex and Gender</title>
		<link href="http://alyx.io/feminism/2014/05/24/trans-people-and-dialectics-of-sex-and-gender/"/>
		<updated>2014/05/24</updated>
		<id>http://alyx.io/feminism/2014/05/24/trans-people-and-dialectics-of-sex-and-gender</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;!-- &lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2014-05-24-trans-people-and-dialectics-of-sex-and-gender/trans-flag.png&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2014-05-24-trans-people-and-dialectics-of-sex-and-gender/trans-flag.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 --&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I propose a framework for a non-liberal, non-radical, and non-transmisogynistic feminism: a proletarian feminism. This work builds upon a materialist analysis of &lt;a href=&quot;http://anti-imperialism.com/2014/02/24/on-the-social-construction-of-sex-part-1/&quot;&gt;sex as a social construct&lt;/a&gt; (more available &lt;a href=&quot;http://alyx.io/educational-resources/trans/#sex-binary&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), which is essential reading before you continue. For those unaware of dialectics some parts of this essay may be hard to follow, so I recommend reading an &lt;a href=&quot;http://anti-imperialism.com/2013/12/24/a-short-primer-on-dialectics/&quot;&gt;introduction&lt;/a&gt; if you haven’t encountered this concept before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-basis-of-sexism&quot;&gt;The Basis of Sexism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern radical feminist thought can be summed up as arising from this basic premise:&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:radfeminism&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:radfeminism&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Patriarchy is a caste system which takes humans who are born biologically male or female and turns them into the social classes called men and women.
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deepgreenresistance.org/en/who-we-are/radical-feminism-faqs&quot;&gt;Deep Green Resistance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, sex and gender exist in a dialectical relationship. Although he made no conceptual distinction between sex and gender, Engels in &lt;em&gt;The Origin of the Family, Private Property and the State&lt;/em&gt; summed up the development of patriarchy roughly as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agriculture was invented,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;which lead to the development of a surplus,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;enabling some to live off the labour of others,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;leading to the development of class society.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Class society necessitates that lines of inheritance be identified and secured,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;leading to sexual control of those capable of pregnancy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would add a seventh point onto this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		this necessitated a socially constructed category (&quot;sex&quot;) to arise, seperating:
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;those who were able to become pregnant&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;from those who couldn&#39;t become pregnant&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some may object to Engels’ conclusion, stating that “even in pre-class societies gender [roles] still existed”, but this argument makes the mistake of falsely projecting current social relations into the past. There was a fuzzy and inexact “division of labour” (in the hunting/gathering sense) based on physical fitness and capability, and so it follows that the share of work would have fallen &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; roughly and haphazardly along the lines of what we’d &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; call “gender” in our current social context, but this was nothing like gender roles or gendered oppression, and didn’t constitute a category of domination or exploitation. Pre-class societies, having no surplus, required that everyone work exactly or near-exactly according to their physical capabilities because there simply wasn’t the productive capacity to allow for the inefficiency of gender roles caused by sex classifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What of gender, then? Where does it fit into these seven points?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a qualitative shift in the development of sex relations; patriarchy transcended and shifted from its original solely sex-based form into a sex and gender-based one. Class society caused sex, and sex in turn caused gender. “Gender” is when sexism, oppression and exploitation based on reproduction (and ultimately relations of production), is institutionalized and divorced from each individual person’s reproductive capacity and general biology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without sex, sexism wouldn’t have ever arisen, but an individual person’s “sex”, as decided by society, doesn’t completely determine their relationship to sexism. Designation at birth isn’t some metaphysical essence that’s imparted on someone for life, entirely and necessarily coloring all further social interactions. Designation at birth is of course an incredibly powerful predictor of the ensuing privileges, socialization, and sex education society places upon someone, and this absolutely cannot be denied. But as ever, as with all generalisations, it isn’t correct in every case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confusion of the conditions for the creation and development of oppressor and oppressed classes with the conditions for oppression in a mostly individual context is one of the most infuriating aspects of radical feminism. The categories of “&lt;abbr title=&quot;Designated Female At Birth&quot;&gt;DFAB&lt;/abbr&gt;” and “&lt;abbr title=&quot;Designated Male At Birth&quot;&gt;DMAB&lt;/abbr&gt;” developed in tandem with the development of the gender hierarchy, but that doesn’t mean that each individual person’s place in the gender hierarchy is necessarily what one would traditionally expect for a person of their birth designation. To think otherwise is a classic misunderstanding of the relationship between the aggregate and the particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re a trans woman or a cis woman – at least on the surface – doesn’t matter to those enforcing patriarchy. Even those trans women gendered as “freaks” or “gender traitor men” and not “cis woman” still receive womanhood, maybe not always as a label, but certainly on the end of male violence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The categories of “womanhood” and “manhood” weren’t created for anything, they weren’t created &lt;em&gt;specifically&lt;/em&gt; and with some sort of supernatural intent to oppress the categories of “female” and “male”, as some propose. Those concepts weren’t brought into existence by anything sentient, there’s no real mystical “purpose” to them. Manhood is imposed (or granted) on the oppressor class, and womanhood (or “&lt;a href=&quot;https://radtransfem.wordpress.com/2011/12/12/genderternary-transmisogyny/&quot;&gt;genderfreakhood&lt;/a&gt;” for trans women sometimes) imposed on the oppressed class. That’s really all there is to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the above radical feminist quote and expanding and adapting it in light of our proletarian feminist understanding, we get the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patriarchy is a caste system arising from class society. Class society created the social construct of “sex”, which in turn paved way for the social construct of “gender”. Gender turns humans, broadly, into the social classes “woman” and “man”, these classes are &lt;em&gt;structurally&lt;/em&gt; (not individually) dependent on the social classes “female” and “male”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sex categories of today and of past class societies would not exist outside of their respective relations of production. Just like it’s exploitation that creates gender and not the contrary, it’s exploitation that creates sex, and not the contrary. The contrary would be to say that sex creates exploitation – to say that the origin of exploitation lies in sex itself – in a natural division of humanity outside of society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, women’s role in society stems from class society, not biology. It is only when biology enters into a social relationship with class society and the social construct of “sex” arises that women are controlled. Without women, there would be no heirs, and without heirs no inherited property or lines of class succession. The category of sex is the product of class society in which men colonize as property the reproduction of women, just as as animals, peoples, nations, lands, and natural resources were colonized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gender-identity&quot;&gt;Gender Identity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three sites of contradiction within the concept of “gender identity” for trans people:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;self↔body:&lt;/strong&gt; private feelings about body – “this body shape feels personally wrong to me.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;self↔society:&lt;/strong&gt; social feelings about gendered relationships – “this gender role feels wrong to me.”, “people gendering me this way feels wrong to me.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;society↔body:&lt;/strong&gt; social feelings about body – “this body makes people think I’m $gender.”, “I’m uncomfortable with the social meaning attached to this body”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These three relationships are, in turn, dialectically related to one another.  Development and change happens through internal quantitative change in some combination of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the attitudes of society,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the morphology of the body,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;or the personality or personal circumstances of the trans person,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this quantative change drives an external, qualitative, change in a relationship, and is characterized by temporary bouts of self-doubt or dysphoria. This moves in a spiral pattern, with the contradictions getting ever sharper, until the person comes out. No one will experience this process exactly alike, and the principle contradictions will be different for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prevailing notion – at least in liberal feminism – that dysphoria causes transness is wholly wrong. An equally wrong idea, popular for radical feminists, is the view that transness causes dysphoria. There’s no one-way causal relationship; instead, they co-emerge. They’re in a feedback loop, forever remaking, reforging, and reshaping each other. Utterly inseparable, yet distinct at the same time. The spiral metaphor applies very aptly here as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HRT and surgery can generally resolve the &lt;em&gt;self↔body&lt;/em&gt; contradiction, and this is also true, though maybe to a lesser degree (and also depending on luck), for the &lt;em&gt;society↔body&lt;/em&gt; contradiction. Activism or revolution can resolve &lt;em&gt;society↔body&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;self↔society&lt;/em&gt;. These three points, self, body, society, are all intimately interconnected, changing one changes the other, and none can be considered static or immalleable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common line from trans activists that trans people’s gender is entirely uninfluenced by gender roles is just as a ridiculous proposition as the converse line from radical feminists, that trans people’s gender is entirely influenced by gender roles. In actuality, gender roles are going to have a differing effect based on the social, historical, and individual context of the person in question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should staunchly combat the reactionary subsections of the trans population &lt;em&gt;overtly&lt;/em&gt; influenced by gender roles in their decision to transition as this only serves to reinforce gender roles and provide a smaller space in which “womanhood” or “manhood” can reside. Radical feminists rightly criticize this to some degree but draw the wrong conclusions, and liberal feminists fail to engage with this at all. We must be very careful in our own criticisms here, however, as some people take any trans woman’s display of femininity – regardless of the reasons – as automatically illegitimate, as a sign that they’re “faking” or “appropriating” womanhood, or that they’re some sort of drag queen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should wholly reject the biological-essentialist “brain sex” framework that liberal feminists cozy up to, but radical feminists rightly oppose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should wholly reject the notions of a hard divide between cis and trans people. It’s both theoretically and experientially unsound. A recent study&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; found that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;About 33% of men and 38% of women felt both as a man and as a woman&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;About 30% of men and 45% of women expressed a dislike of their sexed body&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;41% of men and 46.8% of women experience themselves to some extent as two genders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;36.6% of the [non-trans] subjects reported that they sometimes feel like the ‘other’ gender&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;63.7% reported that they sometimes wish to be the ‘other’ gender&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;41.9% were sometimes discontent with their sexed body&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;privilege&quot;&gt;Privilege&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notion that trans women have male privilege is laughable, and oft-times astoundingly hypocritical. Why do we never hear anything about the “straight privilege” of non-trans queers? Why is “raised heterosexual” a term never to grace the lips of anyone discussing non-trans queers? Why are people quick to the draw with “socialized [fe]male” but not “socialized cis”?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone in the world is presented with ideas about womanhood and manhood, maleness and femaleness, regardless of – but of course varying in concordance with – their birth designation. Radical feminists have the direction of causality mixed up, it’s not that your sex completely determines your socialization, it’s that socialization is partly determined by sex designation at birth. People aren’t so much socialized &lt;em&gt;into&lt;/em&gt; a gender role, but educated about gender role&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;, plural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ordered by increasing importance, we can break down the factors needed (in some combination) for someone to have male privilege:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;education about gender roles through the male lens&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;acting out male gender roles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;internalization of male gender roles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;being granted the male gender role by others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These four points can be further split into three distinct periods:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pre-everything&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;post-coming-out to yourself&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;post-coming-out to the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A trans woman on coming out to herself soon drops internalized male privilege and starts to internalize female gender roles. On coming out to the world, she very quickly leaves behind the last point of the first list, the male role granted by others onto her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some trans women may find themselves subconsciously identifying to some degree with women before they come out to themselves. Once a trans woman comes out to herself she’ll very quickly feel like an imposter, she’ll be scared that she’ll be found out at any moment, that she’ll be identified as a gender traitor. Someone thought by others to be something they’re not is never going to fully exercise the privileges granted onto that group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trans women may have experienced limited aspects of male privilege in the past, but once she starts living life as a trans woman most of the time these quickly become overshadowed by her new experiences and socialization, leaving in any relevance only the knowledge of how men talk and act when they think no women are around. Trans women after coming out face much worse (on average) daily material circumstances and much more extreme degrees of misogyny than cis women generally receive,&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; doing a great job of nullifying past experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone active in the trans community long enough will have heard horror stories about older transitioners, and if we absolutely must talk about trans women having male privilege, it’s probably them. I suspect that older transitioners will have experienced the four points in my privilege dissection for long enough in the pre-everything period such that – maybe at least initially – those years stand a much greater chance of overshadowing the post-transition period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what does this simplistic view of socialization and male privilege mean for feminist praxis in general? A feminist praxis stuck in the rut of socialization mythology is an unscientific and dogmatic one unable to correctly respond to changing circumstances. There’s no such thing as a universal female socialization. Female socialization will always be tempered by the ever different material circumstances. In fact, it’s the patriarchs who’d ideally have us receive something approaching a universal socialization. If the feminist movement is to accept the myth of universal female socialization it means, by default, universalizing the socialization of the most privileged subsections of women, it means ignoring the differing socialization of all intersectionally oppressed women, not just trans women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gender-role-conformity&quot;&gt;Gender Role Conformity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some trans people suddenly conforming to gender stereotypes after transition isn’t terribly surprising given the unavoidable sexism and cissexism in this society. The impossibly inhuman digitally-manipulated model with a clothing size of “negative-five” isn’t a standard that trans people are mystically exempt from. Some may start to conform in an attempt to justify their transness and legitimize or rationalize their gender, not only to themselves but to others as well. Others, especially trans women and those who also face transmisogyny, may even consciously choose to conform to some degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a trans woman chooses to wear a dress instead of a t-shirt and jeans so that she might stand a better chance of appearing normative and gaining conditional cis privilege, can you really wholly blame her for that instance of conformance? Street harassment, violence, housing and employment discrimination, sexual assault, rape, and more, are the daily lives of “non-passing” &lt;abbr title=&quot;Coercively Assigned Male At Birth&quot;&gt;CAMAB&lt;/abbr&gt; people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can personally attest to this. The fundamentals of my wardrobe haven’t altered, I’m still a hoodie, jeans, and t-shirt kind of person. The only thing that’s changed since I came out is the fit and cut of the clothing I choose to wear to avoid getting misgendered or placed as trans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capitulation with the more “institutional” axis of oppression to save oneself from the more “individual” axis of oppression is hardly a phenomenon unique to trans people; let’s not forget that cis people also face pressure to mold themselves into gender stereotypes. Women wear makeup, black people straighten their hair, autistic people hide their stimming, queer couples avoid holding hands on the street. These specific examples of conformance aren’t even generally in the same league as trans people’s, as succumbence doesn’t usually deny them absolutely vital medical care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aim is to help trans people overcome these sorts of pressures, not punish them for it, and certainly not automatically use it as an excuse to discredit trans people as a whole. There’s no arduous “real life experience” test from a board-certified “homothesiologist” that non-trans queers have to go through to get recognition as queer, but every step of the way, from siblings, parents, friends, doctors, counselors, psychologists, the whole gamut, every single minutiae of trans people’s lives are scrutinized. There’s an eternal and grueling game of Spot The Difference, a hopelessly idealized gender role on the left and the trans person on the right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gender&quot;&gt;Gender&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Womanhood and manhood are defined by their existence &lt;em&gt;through each other&lt;/em&gt; and their violent struggle &lt;em&gt;against one another&lt;/em&gt;. You can’t have one without the other, a contradiction (and an antagonistic one at that) in dialectics parlance. One is the struggle of the oppressed and one the struggle of the oppressor. The call for the abolishment of gender isn’t quite correct, or at least requires a bit more nuance and elaboration. Women and men are not the problem, to be abolished on equal terms, it’s men who are the main problem. That’s where we need to focus our energy. You don’t abolish classes by trying to abolish the proletariat and the bourgeoisie both together, no, you focus on the bourgeoisie. You focus on the exploiters and the dominant class in the dialectic – you abolish men first and foremost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only progressive way forward for men is for them to strive to end class society – the conditions which gave rise to gender – and to give up manhood, to abdicate their patriarchal throne. To consciously decide to fight sexism at every opportunity and to politically, materially, and ideologically, disassociate as much as possible from their privileged position, masculinity, and exploitation of women. To try and undermine their own social position at every turn. Progressive men should stop trying to envision a “better” manhood or a “better” masculinity; men hurt themselves, other men, women, and non-men when they assert their masculinity, and they should stop trying to imagine ways to redeem themselves without fundamental change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like I strive to give up and end my position and the category of first world labour aristocrat, my position of whiteness, and my position of physical abledness, I call on men to strive to give up manhood. It doesn’t mean I shrug off the label “white” or “labour aristocrat”, just the positioning of those identities as good, or at worst neutral. It means that I recognise that they are fundamentally oppressive social positions and that the only possible use for them are as political organizing labels and for the recognition of my own privilege.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say “I’m a woman” I’m not saying I innately “feel or identify like a woman” (I don’t think you can ever construct a non-patriarchal justification for that), I’m instead relating myself to other women and our somewhat shared experience as a group under patriarchy. I’m stating that my material interests and experience of the world are mostly aligned with womanhood, that my liberation is therefore fundamentally and intimately bound up with other women, and thus as far as I’m concerned, “woman” generally describes me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I “identify” with womanhood because it describes my political experience. It’s the category, or near enough (“genderfreakhood” is also pertinent), that is imposed on me. When I’m gendered woman, I am woman. When I’m not gendered woman, I’m not woman. Like the other oppressive social constructs – blackness or queerness for example – “identification” with them for this reason isn’t reification, but a recognition of the political and social reality of other’s reification of the concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My birth designation doesn’t matter. When I’m walking down the street, people gender me as “not male”, as a woman, and it makes me uneasy. When people spew biotruths or make sexist jokes, I know it’s aimed at me. When I see women objectified over and over and over again, I can’t help but learn to hate myself. When I hear about rampant rape, sexual assault, and general violence, I wonder, might I become one of those statistics? Even before I transitioned and started changing my body, the sexism I encountered was still generally aimed at people of a body type I needed for my health. Whenever I interact with a man there’s always a nagging in the back of my mind, how are gender relations coloring this interaction? Again and again, I constantly face misogyny – I face a form of womanhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feminism&quot;&gt;Feminism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all you’ve read here, I think it’s fair to say that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liberal feminism holds a metaphysical conception of both gender and sex&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Radical feminism holds a metaphysical conception of sex and a quasi-materialist and reductionist view of gender&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use “metaphysical” here to mean an analysis that places gender or sex as “natural and inevitable truths”, as a prioris. As something essentially static and existing above or outside history and society. This means regarding sex or gender as anything other than social constructs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use “quasi-materialist and reductionist” here to mean an analysis that considers gender solely on it’s own terms, largely uninfluenced by other concerns. This means, for radical feminists, correctly identifying it as a social construct, but failing to properly situate gendered oppression within the context of class society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liberal feminism finds no problem incorporating trans people into its philosophy as there are no constraints from being fundamentally disengaged with reality. Liberal feminists make an effort to appear trans-inclusive (and most often only to score points against radical feminism in a sort of spiteful or superficial inclusion-theater) by erasing and writing off the influence and role of biology and “sex” in the development and functioning of patriarchy, with obvious theoretical and practical failures, and thus misogynistic consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radical feminism is a more interesting case. The combination of metaphysical and quasi-materialist views of sex and gender respectively produces transmisogyny. There is no saving or redeeming radical feminism of this as some have tried to do. It’s at the very core, the chauvinism is inescapable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the heart of radical feminist attacks on trans people is the notion of biological determinism. If the category of “women” is solely based on biology and women are oppressed specifically because of their reproductive organs, rather than a much deeper interplay between biology and the social-economic context, then trans women are natural enemies on the same level as men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radical feminists have successfully flipped the script, erasing their own essentialism, instead making it appear as if they are the ones valiantly battling against another kind of gender essentialism, one that trans people are automatically and always enforcing. They sing the same melody to a different tune. When they argue that trans people reinforce biological determinism, they avoid the question that if gender is a social construct, why can’t the gender one receives from society change?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radical feminists contradict their desire to abolish gender when they claim that trans women can’t be “legitimate women” because they don’t know what it means to be oppressed as “real biological women”, essentialising the very category they decry others for essentialising! Trans women experience the very real pressures of sexism every day of their lives, and no amount of sophistry can change this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:radfeminism&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I recognise that this definition of modern radical feminism isn’t correct in all contexts, but for this specific topic it is the most accurate and to-the-point. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:radfeminism&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/19419899.2013.830640#.Ukw0G7wVwb0&quot;&gt;Queering Gender: Studying Gender Identity in ‘normative’ Individuals&lt;/a&gt;. The percentages here are probably on the low side, given the strength of institutional cisness. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetaskforce.org/reports_and_research/ntds&quot;&gt;Injustice at Every Turn: A Report of the National Transgender Discrimination Survey&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>13 Notes on Innovation in Socialism and Communism</title>
		<link href="http://alyx.io/marxism/2014/04/29/notes-on-innovation-in-socialism/"/>
		<updated>2014/04/29</updated>
		<id>http://alyx.io/marxism/2014/04/29/notes-on-innovation-in-socialism</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All levels of education would be free for all people. Socialist (or at least nominally socialist) states have always put a huge emphasis on education. Cuba, a third-world country, is a shining example with the world’s highest literacy rate, and a ratio of one teacher to every 12 students.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Duplicated effort would be eradicated, and collaborative effort would take its place, with the disappearance of corporate secrecy and competition.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Innovation along the lines of bourgeois logic would be deprecated in favor of innovation according to the needs of humanity. The huge amount of labour expended on things like improving the effectiveness of advertising, the profits of the banks, the snoopiness of state spying apparatus, or the deadliness of weapons of mass destruction would be put to better use.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The patent and copyright system would be abolished. People would be free to hack upon any work without restriction.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The stark toll on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/science/2013/aug/29/poverty-mental-capacity-complex-tasks&quot;&gt;mental&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.post-gazette.com/news/health/2013/11/25/CHILDREN-and-POVERTY/stories/201311250024&quot;&gt;physical&lt;/a&gt; wellbeing from poverty would be eradicated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The pressures and distractions of monetary concerns would be thrown to the wayside. The straining and stressing of the mind from an ever-present threat of the chains of unemployment, bankrupty, or just the worries of choosing whether to put food in mouths or pay off the credit card interest for the month, would be gone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creative and inventive labour wouldn’t be alienated. Innovation would ultimately be for you and the whole people, not for the further enrichment of a certain, already enriched, class.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rather than help it, research has shown that rewards – bringing money into the equation – for even rudimentary cognitive work actually &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tJr9QajdCNc&quot;&gt;harms performance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Discrimination would actively be combatted. Talented people would get a proper and full chance to shape the world without the fetters and challenges of oppression.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full employment would be provided. A constant 5% to 15% (and sometimes even more) of working-age people wouldn’t be denied jobs. More people would be granted the chance at innovation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since ever increasing monopolisation (an absolutely &lt;a href=&quot;http://marxistupdate.blogspot.co.uk/2011/07/lenins-imperialism-still-relevant-today.html&quot;&gt;undeniable&lt;/a&gt; empirical fact, by the way) is an unavoidable law of the development of capitalism, liberals have backed themselves into a corner with “competition” being the sole premise for their position on innovation. Competition-based arguments – if we even accept their validity in the first place – are not sustainable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The profit motive, another one liberals cite, can actually be a hamper to innovation according to human need. Two examples are:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Antibiotic-resistant bacteria are becoming ever more common, and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://theconversation.com/antibiotic-crisis-grows-while-drug-companies-make-lifestyle-meds-4373&quot;&gt;huge crisis looms&lt;/a&gt;, but since antibiotics are only needed for a short time, pharmaceutical companies – and they have admitted this themselves – choose to develop treatments for more profitable chronic (and generally less deadly) conditions instead.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Malaria, being primarily a disease of the poor regions of the world, gets &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.co.uk/news/archive/2013-03/14/bill-gates-capitalism&quot;&gt;less research funding&lt;/a&gt; than male pattern baldness.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With the disappearance of private property, huge portions of the legal system constraining innovations from being used and innovators innovating, would be gone.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A vaccine for the ebola virus for the 2014 outbreak, ready to save potentially &lt;em&gt;millions&lt;/em&gt; of people if it gets out of hand, was &lt;a href=&quot;http://io9.com/ebola-vaccine-delay-may-be-due-to-an-intellectual-prope-1642035584&quot;&gt;held up for months due to “intellectual property” disputes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Binding ctrl+(shift+)tab in GTK3</title>
		<link href="http://alyx.io/programming/2014/03/02/ctrl-(shift)-tab-shortcut-in-gtk3/"/>
		<updated>2014/03/02</updated>
		<id>http://alyx.io/programming/2014/03/02/ctrl-(shift)-tab-shortcut-in-gtk3</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;problem&quot;&gt;Problem&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pressing &lt;code&gt;ctrl+shift+tab&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ctrl+tab&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;shift+tab&lt;/code&gt; never fires a &lt;code&gt;key-pressed-event&lt;/code&gt;, but is instead gobbled up internally by GTK3 and used to switch the currently focused widget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is especially annoying when dealing with the &lt;code&gt;GtkNotebook&lt;/code&gt; widget, as the de-facto, cross-platform, standard for switching tabs involves, well, the tab button. The “alternative” shortcut GTK3 offers is &lt;code&gt;ctrl+pageup&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;ctrl+pagedown&lt;/code&gt; but this is by all accounts, objectively inferior. It requires two hands, and switching between tab-forwards and tab-backwards mode requires moving a finger across keys (whereas the normal shortcut only requires lifting one finger).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;solution&quot;&gt;Solution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GTK3 offers the &lt;code&gt;focus&lt;/code&gt; signal which is emitted by the currently focused widget every time &lt;code&gt;tab&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;shift+tab&lt;/code&gt; is pressed. This is intended to be overridden if the programmer is creating their own widget, but we can use it for our purposes and instead of changing the focused widget, switch the active tab in our notebook. Since the actual tab switching has to happen inside the &lt;code&gt;focus&lt;/code&gt; callback we’ll also need &lt;code&gt;key-pressed-event&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;key-released-event&lt;/code&gt; callbacks to record inside a global variable whether the control key is currently pressed or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-cpp&quot; data-lang=&quot;cpp&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;bool&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;controlPressed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// user_data = whether this is a callback for a keydown (else a keyup)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;bool&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;control_key_checker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GtkWidget&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;widget&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GdkEventKey&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gpointer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;user_data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keyval&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GDK_KEY_Control_L&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;controlPressed&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;bool&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;user_data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;bool&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;notebook_tab_shortcut&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GtkWidget&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;widget&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GtkDirectionType&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;direction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gpointer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;user_data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;controlPressed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;last&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gtk_notebook_get_n_pages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GTK_NOTEBOOK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;user_data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;current&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gtk_notebook_get_current_page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GTK_NOTEBOOK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;user_data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;next&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;direction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;next&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;current&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;last&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;current&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;next&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;current&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;last&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;current&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gtk_notebook_set_current_page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GTK_NOTEBOOK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;user_data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;next&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-cpp&quot; data-lang=&quot;cpp&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;argc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;argv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[])&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[...]&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;g_signal_connect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;focus&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G_CALLBACK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;notebook_tab_shortcut&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gpointer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;notebook&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;g_signal_connect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;key-press-event&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G_CALLBACK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;control_key_checker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gpointer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;g_signal_connect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;key-release-event&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;G_CALLBACK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;control_key_checker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gpointer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[...]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full, runable, example is available &lt;a href=&quot;/uploads/2014-03-02-ctrl-(shift)-tab-shortcut-in-gtk3/gtk-tab-shortcut.cpp&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Solving World Hunger in 6.9 Days – The 256 Most Profitable Corporations</title>
		<link href="http://alyx.io/capitalism/2014/01/21/corporate-profit-world-hunger/"/>
		<updated>2014/01/21</updated>
		<id>http://alyx.io/capitalism/2014/01/21/corporate-profit-world-hunger</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    You&#39;ve been here for:
    
    &lt;h1&gt;
        &lt;b id=&quot;hours&quot;&gt;00&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;b id=&quot;minutes&quot;&gt;00&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;b id=&quot;seconds&quot;&gt;00&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/h1&gt;
    
    Since then the top 256 most profitable corporations in the world have made
    
    &lt;h1&gt;
        $&lt;b id=&quot;accumulation&quot;&gt;0&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/h1&gt;
    
    in pure profit. Solving world hunger would take just $32 billion per year. The profit so far is enough to lift
    
    &lt;h1&gt;
        &lt;b id=&quot;people&quot;&gt;0&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/h1&gt;
    
    starving people out of hunger.
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;h4&gt;***&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    In total, it would take just
    
    &lt;h1&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;6.9 days&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/h1&gt;
    
    to solve world hunger for the year.
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;h4&gt;***&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;h2&gt;
        What could we do with the other 358 days?
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    
    &lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sources and math:&lt;/p&gt;
        
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Corporate profit data from Forbes &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/global2000/list/&quot;&gt;Global 2000 Leading Companies&lt;/a&gt;, May 2013.&lt;/li&gt;
        
        &lt;li&gt;Cost of solving world hunger from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/NEWSROOM/en/news/2008/1000853/index.html&quot;&gt;Food and Agricultural Organization of the United Nations&lt;/a&gt;, inflation adjusted to 2013 dollars.&lt;/li&gt;
        
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/uploads/2014-01-21-corporate-profit-world-hunger/corporate-profit-calculations.ods&quot;&gt;corporate-profit-calculations.ods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        
        &lt;li&gt;Fun fact: sorting by revenue instead of profit returns $674,578 every single second.&lt;/li&gt;
        
        &lt;li&gt;Doubly Fun fact: We actually already produce enough food to feed the population of the world &lt;a href=&quot;/educational-resources/class/#food&quot;&gt;1.5 times over.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;
    // InstantClick.on(&#39;change&#39;, timerShit);
    timerShit();

    function timerShit() {
        var minutesLabel = document.getElementById(&quot;minutes&quot;);
        var secondsLabel = document.getElementById(&quot;seconds&quot;);
        var hoursLabel   = document.getElementById(&quot;hours&quot;);
        var accumulationLabel = document.getElementById(&quot;accumulation&quot;);
        var peopleLabel       = document.getElementById(&quot;people&quot;);

        var totalSeconds = 0;

        setInterval(setTime, 1000);

        function pad(val) {
            var valString = val + &quot;&quot;;
            
            if (valString.length &lt; 2)
                return &quot;0&quot; + valString;
            else
                return valString;
        }

        function setTime() {
            ++totalSeconds;
            
            secondsLabel.innerHTML = pad(totalSeconds % 60);
            minutesLabel.innerHTML = pad(parseInt(totalSeconds / 60) % 60, 10);
            hoursLabel.innerHTML   = pad(parseInt((totalSeconds / 60) / 60), 10);
            
            accumulationLabel.innerHTML = (totalSeconds * 54020).toLocaleString();
            peopleLabel.innerHTML       = (totalSeconds *  1434).toLocaleString();
        }
    }
&lt;/script&gt;

</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>My xmonad Config</title>
		<link href="http://alyx.io/gnu/linux/2013/09/16/my-xmonad-config/"/>
		<updated>2013/09/16</updated>
		<id>http://alyx.io/gnu/linux/2013/09/16/my-xmonad-config</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After many hours of tweaking, starting on the shores of xmobar/demu and later ending up in gnomeConfig waters, I think I’ve finally settled on something approaching a completed config. The default gnomeConfig is so close to being perfect, yet it misses out with a lack of libnotify support (and, due to the limitations of the gnome workspace switcher, doesn’t handle multiple monitors, but that’s for another day).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/images/2013-09-16-my-xmonad-config/tiling.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2013-09-16-my-xmonad-config/tiling.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;sudo add-apt-repository ppa:richardgv/compton&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; sudo apt-get update&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; sudo apt-get install xmonad libghc-xmonad-dev libghc-xmonad-contrib-dev compton roxterm gnome-panel&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re using apt, and a non-exotic display manager, an entry for xmonad/gnome should appear automatically on the log-in screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;xmonad.hs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-haskell&quot; data-lang=&quot;haskell&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;XMonad&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;XMonad.Config.Gnome&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;XMonad.Hooks.ManageHelpers&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;XMonad.Hooks.UrgencyHook&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;XMonad.Actions.CycleWS&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;XMonad.Layout.Fullscreen&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;XMonad.Layout.NoBorders&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;XMonad.Util.NamedWindows&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;qualified&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;XMonad.StackSet&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;W&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;qualified&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;Data.Map&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;M&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;--------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- Vars:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;myTerminal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;roxterm&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- gnome-terminal doesn&amp;#39;t set the X11 urgent flag on&lt;/span&gt;
                       &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- the bell character (^G)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;myBrowser&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;firefox&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;myEmail&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;thundbird&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;myFileMan&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;nautilus&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;myEditor&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;sublime-text&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;myMonitor&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;gnome-system-monitor&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;myPiracy&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;transmission-gtk&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;myMusic&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;clementine&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;myFeeds&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;liferea&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

 &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- Blend in with the Ubuntu Ambiance theme&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;myNormalBorderColor&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;#413F3B&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;myFocusedBorderColor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;#A2A094&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;--------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- Urgency Hook:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- Use libnotify notifications when the X11 urgent hint is set&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;LibNotifyUrgencyHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;LibNotifyUrgencyHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;deriving&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;Read&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;Show&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;instance&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;UrgencyHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;LibNotifyUrgencyHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;where&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;urgencyHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;LibNotifyUrgencyHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;w&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;getName&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;w&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wins&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gets&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;windowset&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;whenJust&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;W&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;findTag&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;w&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wins&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;flash&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;where&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;flash&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;index&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spawn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;notify-send &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Workspace &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;index&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39; &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
                                                    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Activity in: &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;show&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39; &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
                                                    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;--icon=notification-gpm-monitor&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;--------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- Window rules:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- To find the property name associated with a program, use&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- &amp;gt; xprop | grep WM_CLASS&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- and click on the client you&amp;#39;re interested in.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;--&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;myManageHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;composeAll&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Bottom Expanded Edge Panel&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;                   &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;--&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;doIgnore&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;className&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Firefox&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Library&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;             &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;--&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;doFloat&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;className&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Firefox&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Firefox Preferences&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;--&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;doFloat&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;className&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;File-roller&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;                                  &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;--&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;doFloat&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;+&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;composeOne&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;isFullscreen&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-?&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;doFullFloat&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;--------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- Keybinds:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;keysToAdd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;modMask&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.|.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shiftMask&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;xK_Left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;prevWS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- Shift to previous workspace&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;modMask&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.|.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shiftMask&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;xK_Right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nextWS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- Shift to next workspace&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;modMask&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.|.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shiftMask&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;xK_Down&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shiftToPrev&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- Shift window to previous workspace&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;modMask&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.|.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shiftMask&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;xK_Up&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shiftToNext&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- Shift window to next workspace&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;modMask&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.|.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shiftMask&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;xK_f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spawn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myBrowser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;modMask&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.|.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shiftMask&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;xK_e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spawn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myEmail&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;modMask&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.|.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shiftMask&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;xK_d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spawn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myFileMan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;modMask&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.|.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shiftMask&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;xK_s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spawn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myEditor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;modMask&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.|.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shiftMask&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;xK_m&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spawn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myMonitor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;modMask&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.|.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shiftMask&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;xK_p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spawn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myPiracy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;modMask&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.|.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shiftMask&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;xK_u&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spawn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myMusic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;modMask&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.|.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;shiftMask&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;xK_l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spawn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myFeeds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;myKeys&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keys&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gnomeConfig&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;M&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;union&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;M&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fromList&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keysToAdd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;--------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- Startup:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- Enable compositing for transparency, shaped windows, smooth transitions, etc.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;--   -f = enable window fading&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;--   -I = opacity step in&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;--   -O = opacity step out&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;--   --backend glx = better performance&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;--   --vsync opengl = doesn&amp;#39;t work for all drivers, see &amp;#39;man compton&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- Rebind backward/forward keys to home/end.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;myStartupHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;X&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;myStartupHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spawn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;compton -f -I 0.10 -O 0.10 --backend glx --vsync opengl&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;spawn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;notify-send &amp;#39;Xmonad Started/Recompiled&amp;#39; --icon=emblem-system&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;--------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- Main:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;xmonad&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;withUrgencyHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;LibNotifyUrgencyHook&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gnomeConfig&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keys&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myKeys&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;terminal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myTerminal&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;layoutHook&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fullscreenFloat&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fullscreenFull&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;smartBorders&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;layoutHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gnomeConfig&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;manageHook&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myManageHook&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;+&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;manageHook&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gnomeConfig&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;startupHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myStartupHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;+&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;startupHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gnomeConfig&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;handleEventHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fullscreenEventHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;+&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;handleEventHook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gnomeConfig&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;normalBorderColor&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myNormalBorderColor&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;focusedBorderColor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myFocusedBorderColor&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I use Synapse as my general-purpose launcher:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2013-09-16-my-xmonad-config/synapse.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2013-09-16-my-xmonad-config/synapse.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;sudo apt-get install synapse&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Men Should do More Childcare than Women</title>
		<link href="http://alyx.io/feminism/2013/07/24/men-should-do-more-childcare-than-women/"/>
		<updated>2013/07/24</updated>
		<id>http://alyx.io/feminism/2013/07/24/men-should-do-more-childcare-than-women</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Calls for an equal childcare contribution from each of the parents involved with a child completely miss the mark, as childcare is only a subset of the work required in the production of a new human being. Pregnancy, breastfeeding (if applicable), &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; childcare are all work. The time – the work – one of the parents spends pregnant and breastfeeding should therefore be offset by an equivalent amount of work spent caring for the child from the other parent(s). Men should do more childcare than women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the numerical specifics I cede the floor to someone more knowledgeable in the area, but for the sake of example we’ll take 11 weeks which is how long, in the United Kingdom, maternity leave can start before the due date. An equitable share in the production of a new human being would then have the father or other parent taking over sole care of the baby for 11 weeks (or possibly longer if breastfeeding is involved) after it is born, or after an agreed upon time. Thereafter both parents would share equally in the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pregnancy, the biologically necessitated involvement in the pre-birth production of a child, for women, being far greater than that of men, offers a compelling case as one of the causes or reasons for the emergence of patriarchy in its current state (and the relative absence of matriarchies). The involvement of men in the production of a child is dependent on the cultural and the economic situation, but biology means that women will always have a minimum level of involvement as they are the ones who have to go through the birthing process.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Trans Healthcare and my Experience at Nottingham Gender Identity Clinic</title>
		<link href="http://alyx.io/feminism/2013/07/01/trans-healthcare-nottingham-gender-clinic/"/>
		<updated>2013/07/01</updated>
		<id>http://alyx.io/feminism/2013/07/01/trans-healthcare-nottingham-gender-clinic</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Any trans person who knows anything about their history will tell you that we haven’t exactly got along with the medical establishment (to say the very least). As hopelessly naïve as I was, I thought things would be at least a little different now, in 2013, after the huge strides in trans activism and awareness in recent years. I thought that even if the care I received turned out to be not so much care, and more “care”, I could still reason with them, that they might just change their mind if I only &lt;em&gt;explained&lt;/em&gt; things to them. Everyone is, deep down, a reasonable person, right? How wrong I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been continually misgendered by one of the so-called “gender specialists”. I’ve been told off for wearing a t-shirt, jeans, and a hoodie, told that I’m not “feminine enough”, that I’m not straight enough, that I’m not emotionally stable enough, that I should be dressing and acting “like a woman” (whatever that is supposed to mean), that I need to find my gender role. I’ve been told that self medicating hormones for more than year and a half isn’t sufficient proof that hormones are right for me, told that I have no right to make decisions for my self, that I’m too contrarian. I’ve been told, I’ve been told, I’ve been told…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;He. Him. His. Boy. Man. Male. Your right to self definition matters not to us. You’re not pleasing to the male gaze. You’re not submissive enough. You haven’t fully learnt and internalised your patriarchal socialisation yet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been told that I need to socialise more, that I don’t have enough friends, that I need to get a job (I did work, but that wasn’t a “proper” job in their eyes), that I just need to “get out more”. Easier said that done when I’m autistic, living with crippling depression, anxiety, and am dancing on the knife edge of suicide. When was the last time you saw “getting a job and friends” a prerequisite to medically necessary treatment? I can just imagine the national outrage if such requirements were in place for heart surgery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It would be a grave mistake, of course, to let someone become a woman before they’ve been taken down a notch. We can’t have anyone with any sense of self worth or agency belonging to the under class.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make matters worse, the Nottingham Gender Identity Clinic requires that (lifted straight out of the &lt;abbr title=&quot;World Professional Association for Transgender Health&quot;&gt;WPATH&lt;/abbr&gt; Standards of Care, the main guideline used in the “treatment of transsexuals”):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Prior to the commencement of hormone therapy […] the General Practitioner will be requested to carry out the following assessment: Full physical examination, including secondary sexual characteristics […]”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m forced to choose between no access to hormones, surgery (if I’m able to pass through yet more asinine requirements), and correct identity documents (getting your gender officially recognised by the state can be difficult if your “new” gender isn’t a “legitimate” one, as authorised by a clinic), or nothing less than sexual assault.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; There is absolutely no reason given, nor any possible reason in existence, for a routine full physical examination before hormone therapy, none.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Baseless, groundless, useless, pointless. Not only do they seek to control what I do with my body, but they seek to pester, poke, prod and pry into my body. Talk about doctor/patient power imbalance…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make matters &lt;em&gt;even&lt;/em&gt; worse, the trans people going to Nottingham Gender Identity Clinic are roughly the subset of trans people who experience body dysphoria, given that Nottingham Gender Clinic is supposed to provide a fix for said dysphoria. For many, including myself, the idea of being “fully physically examined, including secondary sexual characteristics” is horrific in any context, by anyone, in any situation. Unnecessarily forcing someone to go through a hugely embarrassing and emotionally excruciating examination as a requirement to fix the very discomfort the examination aggravates is nothing but cruel. For all their professions of wanting to help, their taking of the Hippocratic oath was an astoundingly hypocritical act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think I’d be overstating if I said that the Nottingham &lt;abbr title=&quot;Gender Identity Clinic&quot;&gt;GIC&lt;/abbr&gt; has blood on their hands. One Belgium study found that the suicide rate dropped from 29.3% to 5.1% after surgery,&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and given that hormones are required for surgery the suicide rate in people who are both pre-surgery and pre-hormones is probably even higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Nottingham Gender Clinic, and trans healthcare at large, not only serve as the gatekeepers of hormones, surgery, and to some extent correct identity documents, but as the defenders of the patriarchal status-quo. Going through their process is a crash-course in the socialisation we didn’t receive from birth. The medical establishment would rather trans people didn’t exist, but since they have to grudgingly accept that we do, the establishment goes to the next “best” thing – making sure that the trans people they let be “legally trans” conform to cisnormative patriarchy and its gender roles as much as humanly possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clinic and its laws and regulations are yet another leaf born from the same tree as the legislation that requires people with uteri to undergo transvaginal ultrasound scans or psychological evaluations before they’re allowed access to abortion. It’s the same patriarchal tools at work that attempt to destroy any sense of agency and humanity left in someone, the very same policing of minds, bodies and beings that’s revelled in by the abortion moralisers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a truly sad state of affairs. I don’t know where I’d be, or if I’d be here at all, if I couldn’t purchase hormones online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-info&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Update:&lt;/b&gt; I finally got a prescription, and it only took 873 days, self-medicating for over two years, and having surgery on my own, to get it!&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nottinghamshirehealthcare.nhs.uk/EasysiteWeb/getresource.axd?AssetID=2541&amp;amp;type=full&amp;amp;servicetype=Attachment&quot;&gt;Nottingham Gender Clinic Protocol (PDF): Role of the General Practitioners, Page 3&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I understand that, as a sad artefact of the privatised insurance industry, full physical examinations are a yearly affair in the United States (and maybe other countries), so this statement may seem a little bewildering to some readers. In the UK, however, full physical examinations or even general check-ups don’t happen at all unless a good reason presents itself, of which being trans certainly is not one. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wpath.org/documents/Standards%20of%20Care%20V7%20-%202011%20WPATH.pdf&quot;&gt;WPATH Standards of Care v7 (PDF): Appendix B, Overview of the Medical Risks of Hormone Therapy, Page 97&lt;/a&gt;. No contraindication that would require a full physical examination is listed in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wpath.org/documents2/socv6.pdf&quot;&gt;WPATH Standards of Care v6&lt;/a&gt; either. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/uploads/2013-07-01-trans-healthcare-nottingham-gender-clinic/Long-term Follow-up: Psychosocial Outcome of Belgian Transsexuals After Sex Reassignment Surgery.pdf&quot;&gt;Long-term Follow-up: Psychosocial Outcome of Belgian Transsexuals After Sex Reassignment Surgery, Sexologies, Volume 15, Issue 2, April–June 2006, Pages 126–133&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Liberal Free Speech Values</title>
		<link href="http://alyx.io/feminism/2013/04/27/liberal-free-speech-values/"/>
		<updated>2013/04/27</updated>
		<id>http://alyx.io/feminism/2013/04/27/liberal-free-speech-values</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whenever anyone either objects to, or tries to stop, hate speech, the inevitable liberal response is something along the lines of “You can’t infringe upon someone’s right to say those things! Free speech!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This line of reasoning falls down the moment you ask the question “Who’s rights are really being infringed upon, and in what way?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Institutionalised oppression (of which individual instances of hate speech partly make up) alienates the oppressed from society, it marginalises them, silences them. It reduces their cultural currency, it pushes their views, feelings, and interpretations of the world towards the social periphery.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; A person living in the face of institutional oppression is living in a culture where violence against them is permissible, a culture where their personhood is always “lesser-than”, and ultimately, a culture in which speaking out is a dangerous act. Above all, bigoted speech harms the speech of entire swathes of people just because they share an irrelevant characteristic like gender, race, sexuality, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bigotry is founded on objectively incorrect ideas and those defending it often betray acceptance of this fact by falling back on banal appeals to the legal institution of free speech. If bigotry was in any way defensible on its own grounds, most defenders of it would attempt to fight the battle on that front, not divert the discussion towards the question of the law with platitudes like “it’s not technically illegal to say this!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two options available on the question of speech:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;disallow hate speech&lt;/strong&gt;: protect the oppressed from further oppression, give them a chance to fully exercise their free speech&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;allow hate speech&lt;/strong&gt;: let the oppressors continue to oppress, allow them to continue to infringe on the oppressed’s right to free speech&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the choice between restricting the freedom of people who say bigoted things (and who would restrict the freedom of people targeted by said bigotry), or restricting the freedom of the people harmed by that bigotry, the choice is clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allowing someone to, through exercising their rights, restrict the rights of someone else puts the entire concept of “rights” in danger. To use a rather crude example, it would be ridiculous to proclaim that everyone should have the right to bodily autonomy, and then go on to say that it’s okay for me to use my bodily autonomy to repeatedly, and for no reason, smash my fist into someone’s face. That would be a blatant violation of &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; bodily autonomy. Conflicts of rights are an inevitability, rights can never be universally extended to everyone in every situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same principle in the above paragraph applies here, exercising your free speech and using it to infringe upon the right of free speech of others defeats the entire purpose of “free speech” in the first place, unless of course, you think that free speech should only be extended to certain members of the non-oppressed population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Stereotypes and Stereotyping, &lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=o2EVqBMpJDEC&amp;amp;lpg=PA193&amp;amp;ots=FRnusjbfq1&amp;amp;pg=PA193#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;Chapter 6: Language and Stereotyping&lt;/a&gt;, Anne Maass &amp;amp; Luciano Arcuri – 1996 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
</feed>
